## Conor W. Hanson

Coon Rapids, MN

608-219-5058 | condorhanson@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/conorwhanson">https://conorwhanson.github.io/portfolio/</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://conorwhanson.github.io/portfolio/">https://conorwhanson.github.io/portfolio/</a> |

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/conorwhanson">https://github.com/conorwhanson</a>

# **Summary**

I am a Data and Information Systems Coordinator in the field of Program Evaluation & Research. I support any and all data & research activities on projects for diverse clients supporting and serving their communities. I primarily work with qualitative data, particularly interview transcripts, Likert scales, and surveys.

I help develop data plans and processes for projects, including data collection methods and processes, data security and privacy compliance (HIPAA & GDPR), data pipeline development utilizing APIs, data cleaning, processing, and analysis, and data visualization.

Furthermore, I build internal data process and systems capacity such as data literacy support, consistent data practices and standards, data security tools and processes, and research new data tools to support both client projects and internal company capacity.

I enjoy bridging communication gaps surrounding data and utilizing data to support diverse communities and perspectives. I seek to learn from under-served and under-resourced communities and support their self-determined goals with data.

I am proficient in Python, and comfortable in SQL, R, Javascript, and HTML.

# **Technical Skills**

## **Programming Languages:**

- Python
- SQL
- R
- JavaScript
- HTML
- JQuery
- VBA

## **Softwares/Platforms:**

- Numerous Python packages: Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Numpy, Flask, Scikit-learn, SQLAlchemy
- GitHub version control
- APIs with Python and JavaScript
- Spark and PySpark
- Natural Language Processing
- Tableau
- Excel
- RStudio
- PGAdmin (PostgreSQL)
- SQLite
- VSCode
- SQLite
- MongoDB
- AWS S3 and RDS
- Machine Learning with TensorFlow and Scikitlearn

#### Education

**Certificate in Data Analysis & Visualization:** University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN March 2022 - September 2022

This was a 24-week intensive bootcamp designed to immerse us in the world and tools of data science. It was heavily focused on data analysis and processing in Python, but included the necessary training with R, SQL and non-relation databases, Big Data storage and processing, ETL development, web app construction, and a good dose of machine learning and neural networks.

**B.A. in Philosophy** (summa cum laude): University of Wisconsin - Stevens Point, Stevens Point, WI 2015 - 2019

Areas of interest/competency: Philosophy of Religion, Philosophical Theology, Christian Theology, Moral Philosophy, Ethics, Metaphysics, Political Philosophy/Political Theory, Logic.

Awards: Continuing Student Scholarship – Department of Philosophy, Spring 2018

Distinguished Achievement Award, Continuing Student in the Department of Philosophy - College of Letters and Sciences, Spring 2018

Boethius Book Award, Spring 2019

**Publications:** "How Dave Chappelle and Saint Augustine Help Us See Ourselves" in *Dave Chappelle and Philosophy: When Keeping It Wrong Gets Real (Pop Culture and Philosophy)* Ed. Mark Ralkowski. Chicago: Open Universe, 2021.

**2-Year Technical Diploma Automotive Technician:** Madison Area Technical College 2008-2010

# **Experience**

## **Data and Information Systems Coordinator**

September 2023 - Present

I research, test, recommend, and develop data and information systems pertinent to company and client needs, harness many APIs and build data pipelines using Python to automate company processes and client project data needs, spearhead development and implementation of internal company data systems and policies, and maintain company software platforms such as Google Workspace and Smartsheet.

### **Research and Data Assistant**

September 2022 - September 2023

I obtained and organized literature/data for review, administered surveys and supported data collection efforts, took and summarized notes at internal and client meetings, organized and co-facilitated focus groups and interviews, recorded and reviewed data for quality, transferred data into spreadsheets, tables, and charts to illustrate key findings, explored, cleaned, and analyzed data, tracked data and supported project teams.

## Stay-at-home-dad

September 2021 - September 2022

I have been the primary caretaker for my daughter since her birth in 2019, but I stayed home full-time with her since September 2021. It was during this time I began my Data Analysis program at the U of M.